Sincro: wyxchari
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
基于 opentitles.org 英文字幕翻译
我们-将会-获得-能量
We will get our power. We will get our power...
重新-打开-电力-供应
Turn back the power supply.
我会的，但我要你们记住，是我控制你们
I will, I will. But I want you to remember that I control you.
我们-是-你的-仆人
We are your servants.
我知道，记住这点：我给了你们每个充了电，这才让你们复活了
I know. Remember it. I gave you each a special charge to bring you back to life.
你们还需要电力的话，都得靠这个发电机来. 由我来控制它，明白了吗?
Any further power you need must come from this generator.
And I control it. Is that clear?
我们-服从
We obey.
他们要去哪里?
Where are they going?
静候-你的-命令 主人
To await your orders, master.
很好. 那个陨石风暴方面的计算机，你完成设计图了吗
Good. Have you completed the blueprints for the meteor storm computer?
已经-好了
It is ready.
噢, 太棒了! 我很高兴我们达成了共识
Oh, it's marvellous! I'm glad we understand each other.
我们-了解-人类-想法
We understand the human mind.
还没完成吗?
Isn't that finished yet?
快了
Nearly.
我是 Valmar. 测试一下通讯
This is Valmar. Test call please.
Terrace. 我能清楚地听见你的声音，很好 现在尝试建立内部连接，然后是周边站点
Terrace. So I can hear you clearly all right, good. Now try and
get in connection now with the interior, and then the perimeter stations.
好了，没问题了
Well, no troubles now.
还算及时. 这项工作早应该完成了
About time. This work should have been completed long before this.
我已经尽了最大努力!
Well, I did the best I could!
是，但还不够!
Well, it isn't good enough!
那你找其他人吧, Bragen.
Then get someone else, Bragen.
小心点! 我会盯着你, Valmar, 从现在开始 - 现在给我出去!
Be careful! I shall be watching you, Valmar, after this - now get out!
这样闯进来是什么意思?
What does this intrusion mean?
抱歉, Bragen. 我没能拦住他们
I'm sorry, Bragen. I tried to stop them.
硬闯进来? 不是硬闯. 你不是要见我们吗，我们就来了
Intrusion? It's no intrusion. We're just returning the various calls that you made.
这个保安跟我们说你一直都忙，但你一点也不忙，是不?
This guard tried to tell us you were busy.
You're not a bit, are you?
好了，我见他们
All right - I'll see them.
喔, 新制服很不错啊. 很醒目. 很醒目. 我想要一顶类似的帽子.
Oh, what a nice new uniform. Very smart, very smart.
I would like a hat like that.
你们想要干什么
Well, what do you want?
某些小丑绑架了 Polly ，送来了这张字条
Some joker has kidnapped Polly and sent us this note.
是啊
Yes.
我们想知道你打算怎样找她
Well, we want to know what you're doing to find her.
现在通讯已经恢复了，我们可以展开搜索
Now that the communications are restored we can start a search.
好，我能想象你将会怎样做. 你没有听说什么吗?
Yeah, I can just imagine what kind of job you'll make of that.
Haven't you heard anything yet?
这个星球很大
The planet is a large one.
他们已经让你来运作整个基地，是吧
So! They've given you the run of the colony, have they?
我们-服从. 需要-给你的-客人-准备-饮料吗?
We obey. Do I bring liquid for your visitors?
不必了. 他们不会呆多久.
No. They won't be staying much longer.
看, 博士, 如果他不打算帮我们, 我们就得自己去找寻 Polly 了.
Look, Doctor, if he's not going to help us,
we'll have to search for Polly ourselves.
好主意, 为什么不去呢, 博士?
Sound advice. Why don't you, Doctor?
哦, 是监察员.
Ah, ah, Examiner.
我很好奇他们怎么能够在这些地板上转来转去?
I wonder how much longer they'll be able to move around on these floors?
呃?
Eh?
地板. 不是金属的.
Floors. They're not metal.
博士.
Doctor.
啊, Bragen 你在啊. 感谢上天通讯恢复了.
Ah, there you are Bragen.
Thank heavens the communications are working again.
糟糕的是我在下边脱不开身.  怎样? 你汇报下情况, 快点. 我的日程安排得很紧.
It's bad enough being stuck out here on the perimeter.
Well? Your report man. Hurry up. I've got a very full schedule.
这里没有什么需要汇报的, 总督.
There is nothing to report, Governor.
监察员呢?
The Examiner?
我把他照顾得很好.
I'm taking good care of him.
好, 你执行得不错.
Good, you know my orders.
是的, 先生.
Yes, sir.
好吧, 有什么事情通过这个联系我, 就这样.
All right, well you can reach me here if you have to, that's all.
等一下, 总督. 你估计什么时候回来?
One moment, Governor. When will you be coming back?
哦, 至少一两天内不行. 你能管好吧?
Oh, not for a day or two at least. You can manage, can't you?
是的, 当然了, 总督.
Yes. Yes of course, Governor.
你想要干什么?
What do you want?
你-有没有-喝完-饮料?
Have you finished your liquid?
没, 我还没有.
No. No I haven't.
你最好检查一下议程.
You'd better check the agenda.
我现在就干.
I'll do it now.
静电你看. 他们需要地板持续提供静电, 某种电力场.
Static you see. They need a constant supply of static
from the floor, some sort of electrical field.
博士, 为什么他会...?
Doctor. Why should he...?
这太疯狂了!
It's madness!
什么?
What is?
允许他们像这样乱跑.
Letting them run around like this.
嘿, 等一下! Bragen 已经有一个做仆人的了, 我们刚离开那里!
Hey, wait a minute! Bragen had one acting as a servant,
and we've just left him!
一个 Dalek 在 Bragen 的办公室 - 三个 Daleks 刚走过了走廊. 总共就是四个!
One Dalek in Bragen's office - three Daleks just gone down
the corridors. That makes four!
第四个哪里来的?
Where did the fourth one come from?
Lesterson 不可能在制造它们.  说不定舱体里面还有一些, 而我们不知道?
Well, Lesterson can't have been making them.
Perhaps there were more in the capsule than we thought?
我们得去看看 Lesterson. 嗯, 同时让他看看这张字条. 也许他或者 Janley 知道 Polly 在哪里.
We must go and see Lesterson. Yeah, and show him this note.
Maybe he or Janley knows where Polly is.
我们上次吓着他了. 我很好奇这个通告栏上有什么这么吸引人?
We frightened him off.
I wonder what the fascination of this notice board is?
我看不过是一个非常普通的通告栏.
It looks like a perfectly ordinary noticeboard to me.
嗯, 来吧, 博士.  我们必须找出是谁抓走了 Polly. 博士, 快点!
Yeah, well come on, Doctor. We must find out who's got Polly.
Doctor, come on!
(板上标题: 基地重要通知)
Janley?
什么事?
What is it?
那些 Daleks. 他们又给了一份清单, 说它们需要这些材料.
The Daleks. They've given me another list of materials they need.
我看看. 我们有这些东西吗?
Let me see. We've got all those things?
有, 不过为什么要这么多, Janley? 他们怎么可能已经用完我给他们的材料了?
Yes, but why these quantities, Janley? Why?
How can they have used up all the materials I gave them?
到底是什么情况? ... 才过了几个小时而已.
What is it? D... why, it's only a matter of a few hours ago.
他们在为我们建设新东西.
They're building new things for us.
是的, 我不想他们做事之前不问我的意见. 他们到底在那里面做什么?
Yes, well I don't want them to do anything without consulting me.
What is it they do inside there?
你担心得过头了.
You're worrying too much.
Janley 你说说你的看法. 不过我开始觉得监察员对 Daleks 的看法是对的
Look Janley, say what you like, but I'm beginning to believe that
the Examiner is right about the Daleks.
他们的想法吓着我了。如果我们能控制住他们, 那还好. 但如果不能...
Their original thinking terrifies me.
If we can control them, fine. But if not...
怎样?
Yes?
那我就要把他们销毁. 这太危险了
Then I shall have them destroyed. It's too dangerous.
监察员知道一些我们不知道的事情. 我要去问问他的建议.
The Examiner knows something about them that we don't.
I'm going to ask his advice.
如果我是你的话, 我不会把监察员扯进来.
I wouldn't bring the Examiner into it if I were you.
为什么不呢?
And why not?
你想让他发现 Resno 的事吗?
You want him to find out about Resno?
哦, 一点小事故. 他怎样了? 好些了吗?
Oh, a little accident. How is he? Is he better?
他死了.
He's dead.
你在说什么呢? 你告诉我说他只是...
What are you talking about? You told me he was...
你当时在忙着搞 Daleks 的实验.
You're busy with the experiments on the Daleks.
但你应该告诉我啊. 不过... 尸体怎么办 - 这事得上报.
But you should have told me. But... but the body
- it'll have to be reported.
别担心, 没人会发现尸体.
Don't worry, no one will find the body.
哦 Janley, 你干了一件很糟糕的事情.
Oh Janley, you've done a terrible thing.
Daleks 的实验更加重要.
The experiments on the Daleks were more important.
比人命更重要? 不, 不, 我不会接受这个.
More important than human life? No. No, I won't accept that.
你会的. 你必须! 是你的粗心大意导致了 Resno 的死亡. 是你杀死了他.
You will. You must! Your carelessness was the cause of Resno's death.
You murdered him.
除了我的证词, 你找不到别人证明
It's only your word against mine.
我不会被你勒索的!
I won't be blackmailed by you!
我想要的只是你继续干你的事. 科学发现不应该在死亡面前停步, Lesterson.
All I want is for you to go on as you are.
Scientific discovery can't stop dead, Lesterson.
我告诉过保安没人可以进来.
I told the guard that no-one was to be allowed in.
"授予一切权限" 记得吗?
"Accord every access" remember?
我们正在找寻 Polly.
We're looking for Polly.
这样啊, 她并不在这里, 我也没看见过她.
Well, she isn't here, and I haven't seen her.
她被绑架了.
Well, she's been kidnapped.
哦, 听起来不太可能啊.
Oh, it sounds a little unlikely.
很可能, 对不? 看, 我们还收到了这样字条, 上面是这样说的.
Oh it does, does it? Well, we've got this note which tells us so.
我很抱歉, 这事我什么也不知道.
I'm very sorry, but I don't know anything about it.
Lesterson?
嗯?
Yes?
你没在建造 Daleks 吧, 有吗?
You haven't been building Daleks, have you?
建造? 不, 我都不知道怎么开始.
Building? No I wouldn't know how to begin.
舱体里面当时只有三个?
And there were only three in the capsule?
是的.
Yes.
但我们刚才看见了四个. 一个在总督的办公室, 三个在走廊!
Well we've just seen four. One in the Governor's office
and three in the corridor!
但那是不可能的啊!
But that's not possible!
这只有一个解释. Daleks 正在自我复制!
There's only one explanation. The Daleks are reproducing themselves!
他们只是机器而已, 怎么能自我复制呢?
These things are machines. How could they reproduce?
机器! 凭什么你认为他们只是机器.
Machines! What makes you think they're just machines.
Daleks 是非常卓越的工程师, 只要有足够的材料, 没谁比他们厉害.
The Daleks are brilliant engineers.
Nothing is beyond them given the right materials.
什么?
What?
我说只要有足够的材料, 没谁比他们厉害.
I said nothing is beyond them given the right materials.
哦...
Oh...
Lesterson, 怎么回事?
Lesterson, what's the matter?
噢...
Oh...
让他一个人呆会儿. 他劳累过度了, 仅此而已.
Leave him alone. He's just been overworking, that's all.
嗯, 他看来比较糟糕.
Well, he looks bad.
你俩能不能离开. 保安! 就是你 - 拿些问题来纠缠他
Will you both go away. Guard! It's you - badgering him with questions.
自从你到 Vulcan 来, 除了干扰他你什么事情都没干.
You've done nothing but hound him ever since you arrived on Vulcan.
Bragen 的命令是不让任何人进来.
Bragen's orders were that no one was to be admitted.
是的, 但是我觉得 ... 监察员....
Yes, but I thought that the... the Examiner.
他攻击了 Lesterson. 把他赶出去. 把他们俩.
He attacked Lesterson. Get them out of here. Both of them.
他没有攻击 Lesterson.
He did not attack Lesterson.
出去, 听见了吗?!
Out, do you hear?!
好吧, 好吧.
All right, all right.
我是 Janley. 告诉 Valmar 马上到实验室来一趟. 好
Janley here. Tell Valmar to come over to the lab right away. Good.
现在没事了. 过来. 在这里休息一下. 你干活干太多了.
Now, it's all right. Come on. Rest here for a bit.
There. You've been doing far too much.
嘘.
Ssssh.
我给他服了镇静剂.
I've sedated him.
喔, 他怎么了?
Well, what's the matter with him?
太累了, 我猜是. 他突然撑不住了.
Overwork, I suppose. He just suddenly broke up.
不过呢, 这给你带来了一个机会, 方便你布 Daleks 要的新电缆.
Anyway, it'll give you a chance to lay in
the new power cable the Daleks have asked for.
你还真会找时机, 对吧?
You don't miss a trick, do you?
我们将要接入你们想要的新电缆.
We're going to lay in the new cables you wanted.
很好.
Good.
你确定这没有问题吗, Janley?
You're sure this is okay, Janley?
当然. 我们帮他们, 他们帮我们.
Of course. We help them. They help us.
是的-我们-是-你们的-仆人.
Yes. We are your servants.
别拖时间, Valmar. 哦, 你看到通告了吧, 是不?
Don't take too long about it, Valmar.
Oh, you saw the notice, did you?
我看到了.
I saw it.
我们还是没有找到 Polly. 在这里闲着做什么呢?
Well, we're still no nearer finding Polly.
What are we hanging about here for?
Ben, 我在文字里看到了一个消息.
Ben, I've found a message in code.
是一种藏头文, 你只要把大写字母挑出来, 看, 你自己试试.
It's an anagram, you just take the capital letters,
see, work it out yourself.
哦, 我不会做填字游戏.
Oh, I can't do crosswords.
今晚会议, 晚上 20:00. R O C K E T - Rocket. R O O M - Room. P.  火箭室 P !
Meeting tonight, 2000 hours. R O C K E T - Rocket.
R O O M - Room. P. Rocket Room P!
这是叛乱分子召集会议的方法, 今晚我们得去那里 - 得早到.
It's the rebels way of calling a meeting.
Only tonight we're going to be there - early.
嘢, 也许能有线索找到 Polly.
Yeah, maybe we're nearer finding Polly than I thought.
啊, 脚麻了, 跟针扎一样.
Aw, I've got pins and needles now.
什么时间了?
What's the time?
到回去的时间了!
Time we went home!
是吧.
Yes.
现在, 我们要展示一点东西. 你们这些区域头目可以把你们看见的事情回去传达一下
Now, we're going to demonstrate something.
You section leaders can pass on what you've seen.
到目前为止, 我们还只是进行了几次破坏活动, 主要是为了试试总督的力量
So far, we've been concerned with testing the strength
of the Governor with a few acts of sabotage.
但现在, 我们准备要夺权了.
But now, we're ready to take over.
这是什么东西? 我看他们来回转, 但只是告诉我们说是 Lesterson 发现的一种机器.
What is that thing? I've seen them moving about,
but all we've been told is that it's a machine Lesterson discovered.
Valmar?
看, 这些 Daleks 是 Lesterson 发现的, 他移除了他们的的武器装备
Well, Lesterson removed the armaments of the Daleks he discovered.
我又重新给这个装上了, 但多接了一个控制器.
I've rearmed this one, but with a controlling device.
我们可以调节枪的火力, 甚至选择是否关闭.
We can regulate the fire power
and turn it off and on whenever we choose.
我们可以演示了吗?
Shall we have the demonstration now?
那是我们要找的人. 他肯定是这个组织的首脑.
That's the one we want. He must be the boss of this outfit.
嘘!
Sssh!
这个屏幕是两英寸厚的钨锰合金. 开始吧, Valmar.
This screen is two inch thick tungsten steel. Right, Valmar.
对着屏幕开火.
Fire at the screen.
安静! 你们必须保持安静. 你们太容易被发现了.
Quiet! You must keep quiet. We're too vulnerable here.
但是你控制不住这样的东西, 它会攻击我们的!
But, you can't control a thing like that. It'll turn on us!
不, 它不会的.
No it won't.
我不会让我的任何一个组靠近这样的东西
I wouldn't let any of my group go anywhere near it.
我可以控制它
I can control it.
证明一下. 啊, 你不敢! 我不是说那个东西对着墙和金属什么的开火, 而是说对着人.
Prove it. Ah, you daren't! I'm not talking about that thing
firing at the wall or bits of metal or anything. I mean people.
你们测试过吗... 你能阻止它们杀人? 我们的人?
Have you tested whether it...
you can stop it from killing people? Our people?
看, 我可以展示一下我们在这里做过什么
Look, I can show you what I've done here.
算了吧. 你怎么知道一个 Dalek 能区别出总督的人和我们的人?
Forget it. How do you know a Dalek can tell the difference
between the Governor's people and our people?
但我可以区别出来啊, 你个笨蛋! 我还就可以控制
But I can tell the difference, you fool! And I control it.
不能光是嘴上说说
We want something better than words.
拿我做实验吧, 这样你能满意吗?
Test it on me. Will that satisfy you?
倒是可以, 不过...
Well yes, but...
她简直是疯了!
She's out of her mind!
这样可以吗?
Is it all right?
现在, 我告诉你开火的时候...
Now, when I tell you to fire...
我-是-你的-仆人.
I am your servant.
回到你的位置上去
Get back to your places.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
当然. 我不会冒不必要的风险
Of course. I don't take needless risks
做得好, Janley.
Oh well done, Janley.
留心你还没有解除 Dalek 的武装! 现在去把枪卸了. 我们不想要任何意外事故.
You haven't disarmed the Dalek! Well go on take the gun away.
We don't want any accidents.
现在说下, 那女孩怎么办?
Now, what about the girl?
我们把她锁起来了, 不用担心
We've got her safely locked up. Never fear.
我觉得我们最好是...
I think the best thing for us to do is...
听到了吗? 说不定他们会说出把她藏哪儿了
Hear that? Maybe they'll say were she is.
谁?
Who's there?
你待在这里, 我去引开他们. 找出 Polly 在哪里
You stay there, I'll distract them. Find out where Polly is.
不!
No!
救命! 救命!
Help! Help!
保安会听见的! 我们得赶紧离开这里! 带走他, 把他锁起来! 快走!
The guards will have heard that! Come on we've got to get out of here!
Take him and lock him up! Quick! Out!
你最好也出来吧. 我们知道你在那儿
You might as well come out. We know you're there.
Bragen!
当然. 否则还有谁适合当这些人的领导?
Of course. Who else is fitted to be leader of the rebels?
毫无疑问你也相当 Daleks 的领导.
No doubt you want to be leader of the Daleks too.
我的确是 Daleks 的领导
I am the leader of the Daleks.
看看你能不能阻止这家伙杀我
Well see if you can stop this one from killing me.
停止! 你听到了, 这是命令. 转身, 去吧保安叫来
Stop! You heard me, that's an order.
Turn away. Fetch the guard.
我-服从
I obey.
你还真会两条腿走路啊, Bragen.
You hope to have it both ways, Bragen.
不过到了总督面前你会变成什么样子, 我会向他揭示你的双重身份的
But how will you look in front of the Governor,
when I explain your dual role to him?
总督不太可能相信一个冒名顶替者的话
The Governor will hardly listen to an impostor.
冒名顶替者? 你打算怎么证明这个?
An impostor? How do you propose to prove that?
我的保安正在水银沼泽打捞那个真监察员的尸体
My guards are now going to produce the body
of the real Examiner from the mercury swamp.
被你谋杀的那个
The one you murdered.
被你假冒的那个
The one you pretended to be.
谋杀罪比冒名顶替严重多了
Murder's a far worse crime than impersonation.
是的, 但你没法证明我是个杀人犯, 而我却可以证明你是假冒的.
Yes, but you can't prove I'm a murderer,
while I can prove that you're an impostor.
把这个人带走. 看住他
Take this man away. Detain him.
一个危险人物
A dangerous man.
现在唯一剩下的就是总督了
Now the only one left is the Governor.
也许我们应该早些搞定这个监察员
Perhaps we should have dealt with the Examiner earlier.
我会及时搞定他的 - 还有Quinn.
I'll deal with him in time - and Quinn.
你是我最没想到会在这里见到的人
You're the last man I expected to see here.
唔. 靠声音驱动的, 是吧?
Hmm. Work's by sound, does it?
我跟你说话呢, 监察员
I'm speaking to you, Examiner.
哦, 抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
如果你一开始肯听我说话, 就不会现在被锁在这里了
If you'd listened to me in the first place,
you wouldn't be locked up here now.
你被关起来倒不是完全没好处, 至少你的敌人露面...
Well your imprisonment hasn't been entirely wasted.
It's brought your enemy out into...
Bragen 是吧? 我一直都知道的.
Bragen? I've known that all along.
是的. 但是你知道吗, 他是叛乱分子的头目
Yes. But, ah, did you know that he was the leader of the rebels?
Bragen? 头目?
Bragen? The leader?
是的. 这是一种很简单的锁, 真的
Yes. It's quite a simple sort of lock, really.
Hensell 的问题在于, 他觉得靠他的个人魅力就可以让这个基地运行良好
Hensell's trouble is he thinks he can run this colony on his personality alone.
但即便他意识到了危险, 他能做什么吗? 叛乱分子组织运作得很好
But even if he knew of the danger, could he do anything?
The rebels are well organised.
总督挺有人气. 他可以指望卫星城的矿工们给他支持
The Governor's popular. He can count on the mine workers
of the perimeter for support.
那样的话我们必须给他带个话
In that case we must get word to him.
如果你认真做好你监察员的工作的话, 你这会儿不会在这里, 我也早出去了
If you'd done your job properly, Examiner,
you wouldn't be here now,and I'd have been out too.
啊是的. 不过呢, 我并不是真正的监察员.
Ah yes. But then, I'm not the real Examiner.
Ben, Polly和我... 我们只是旅行者, 仅此而已.
Ben, Polly and I - We're... we're just travellers, that's all.
当时我们发现监察员死了, 后来发现是 Bragen 谋杀了他
I found the Examiner, dead. Bragen murdered him.
一切事情都回溯到 Bragen. 给我个机会我要把他扳倒
Everything leads back friend Bragen.
Just give me a chance get my hands on him.
我们哪有可能有机会, 除非先能逃出这里
We aren't going to have the chance,
unless we can get out of here.
格子间的门倒是个问题
There's just a little matter of the cell doors.
啊... 噢...
Ah... Oh...
你-叫我-过来?
You sent for me?
在-通讯室-找个-位置  负责-观察 发现-问题-就-报告
Take up a position at the communications room. Watch and report.
我-服从.
I obey.
他们在一起密谋什么! 噢, 我居然没发现?
They're conspiring together! Oh, why didn't I realise?
监察员是对的, 他们是邪恶的!
The Examiner was right. They are evil!
的确有四个. 它们不可能在自我复制吧!
There are four. They can't be reproducing!
九号-Dalek-完成.
Dalek nine complete.
检查
Check.
我们-是-新一代-Daleks!
We are the new race of Daleks!
十号-Dalek-完成
Dalek ten complete.
检查
Check.
十一号-Dalek-完成
Dalek eleven complete.
检查
Check.
十二号-Dalek-完成
Dalek twelve complete.
检查
Check.
十三号-Dalek-完成
Dalek thirteen complete.
完成
Check.
十四号-Dalek-完成
Dalek fourteen complete.
检查
Check.
十五号-Dalek-完成
Dalek fifteen complete.
检查
Check.
十六号-Dalek-完成
Dalek sixteen complete.
检查
Check.
十七号-Dalek-完成
Dalek seventeen complete.
检查
Check.